topresume.com 2019-06-20

# Privacy Policy | TopResume

Thanks for working with us! Here we describe how we collect, use, and handle your information when you use our websites, software, and services (‘Services’).

We at Talent Worldwide Inc. doing business in the United States as TopResume and in the European Union as TopCV (we, us, our, the Company, ‘TopCV’, ‘TopResume’, ‘Talent Inc’) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and ensuring that your personal data (as described in this policy) is processed fairly and lawfully in line with all relevant privacy legislation.

If you are in the European Union, please note that we have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy policy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights please contact our DPO Wendy Kennedy at [DPO@talentinc.com.](mailto:DPO@talentinc.com)

We are committed to compliance with both the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the US-EU Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from Individuals in the European Union member countries and Switzerland. We have certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Privacy Principles of notice, choice, accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity and purpose limitation, access, recourse, enforcement and liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Privacy Principles, the Privacy Shield Privacy Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has jurisdiction over compliance with the Privacy Shield.

### Your Data

As a career development services business, we collect, use, store and transfer the following information to provide, improve, and protect our Services:

_The data we collect and process._ You may give us personal information by visiting the website, filling in forms on the website, using our Services, or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail, or otherwise. This personal information includes the following data which are referred to in this Privacy Policy as ‘your data’, ‘your personal data’ or ‘your personal information’:

  * _Personal information_ you provide when you register to use the website, subscribe to our Service, search for opportunities, enter a promotion or survey, and when you report a problem with the website. The personal information you give us may include your name, address, username and password, e-mail address, payment information (including bank account and payment card details), any information you have included on your CV or resume and feedback and survey responses; 
  * _Technical data_ such as your internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, the web page you visited before visiting our sites, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website; 
  * _Usage data_ which tells us how you use our website, products and services; 
  * _Marketing and communication data_ which tells us your preference in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences; and 
  * _Sensitive personal data_ such as your race or ethnicity, your political opinions, religious beliefs, membership in a trade union, physical or mental health condition, sexual orientation, or criminal offenses. Please note that we do not ask for any sensitive personal information and request that you omit any such information from your CV or resume prior to submitting it to us. 

### How we use your data

  * _Services._ Our Services are designed to make it simple and easy for you to acquire career development products (resumes and CVs LinkedIn accounts, interview preparation services, etc.) To make that possible, we store, use and transmit your data to internal staff and third-party service providers to enable us to register new customers, process payments and deliver our Services. 
  * _Usage._ We also use your data, especially usage data, technical data, and data on how you use our Services, including the actions you take in your account (such as site visits, page interaction information, and search history), to evaluate and improve our Services. 
  * _Cookies and other technologies._ We use technologies like cookies to provide, improve, protect, and promote our Services. For example, cookies help us with things like remembering your username for your next visit, understanding how you interact with our Services, and improving your experience based on that information. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them, please see our Cookie Policy. 
  * _Marketing._ We also use your data to provide you with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (i.e. e-mail) with information about goods and services which are similar to those that have been promoted to you in the past. We will contact you by electronic means only if you have provided your consent for such communication. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, select the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any e-mail communication from us. 

### Sharing your data

We may share information as discussed below, but we won’t sell it to advertisers or third parties.

_Others working for Talent Inc._ Talent Inc. uses trusted third parties (i.e. IT services, analytics services, etc.) to help us provide, improve, protect, and promote our Services. These third parties will access your information only to perform tasks on our behalf in compliance with this privacy policy, and we’ll remain responsible for their handling of your information per our instructions.

We do not disclose personal information to third parties for purposes that are materially different than what it was originally collected for. Should this change in the future, we will provide individuals with the option to opt-out.

We remain liable should a trusted third party to whom we’ve sent your information processes it in a manner inconsistent with this Policy, unless the organization proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

### Protecting your data

Stewardship of your personal data is critical to us and a responsibility we embrace. We have a team dedicated to keeping your information secure and testing for vulnerabilities.

We only process personal data where we have a legal basis for doing so. We review the personal data we hold on a regular basis to ensure it is being lawfully processed and that it is accurate, relevant, and up to date.

Before transferring personal data to any third party (e.g. suppliers, partners, customers, software solution providers, and back office support), we establish that there is a legal reason for making the transfer, which may include your consent.

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

We have implemented measures and procedures that adequately protect the privacy of individuals and ensure that data protection is integral to all processing activities. This includes implementing measures such as:

  * Data minimization (e.g. not keeping data for longer than is necessary);
  * Pseudonymization;
  * Anonymization;
  * Cyber security; and
  * A data security policy.

### Your rights – individuals in the European Union

If you are an individual in the European Union, you have the right to access, correct, restrict, or erase your personal information stored on our platform at any time. You can also exercise any of these rights at any time by contacting us at [privacy@topresume.com.](mailto:privacy@topresume.com) Your rights include the following:

  * _Accessing your data._ Upon request, we shall provide any information relating to your data and our processing of your data in a concise, transparent, intelligible, and easily accessible form using clear and plain language. The information shall be provided in writing or by other means, including, where appropriate, by electronic means within 30 days of a written request. 
  * _Correcting your data._ You have the right to ask us to rectify any inaccurate or incomplete personal data on our platform. If we have given your personal data to any third parties, we will notify those third parties that the Company has received a request to rectify your personal data, unless doing so proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort. Those third parties should also rectify the personal data they hold - however, we are not in a position to audit those third parties to ensure that the rectification has occurred. 
  * _Erasing your data._ You have the right to ask us to rectify any inaccurate or incomplete personal data on our platform. If we have given your personal data to any third parties, we will notify those third parties that the Company has received a request to rectify your personal data, unless doing so proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort. Those third parties should also rectify the personal data they hold - however, we are not in a position to audit those third parties to ensure that the rectification has occurred. 

If we have given your personal data to any third parties, we will tell those third parties that the Company has received a request to erase your personal data, unless this proves impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. Those third parties should also rectify the personal data they hold - however, the Company will not be in a position to audit those third parties to ensure that the rectification has occurred.

_Restricting the use of your data._ We only process your personal data where we have the legal basis for doing so. You have the right to ask us to suspend or otherwise restrict the processing of your personal data where:

  * You challenge the accuracy of the personal data;
  * The processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it;
  * We no longer need the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you want us to hold it as you need it to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims; or
  * You have objected to our use of your data, but we need to verify whether we have legitimate grounds to use it.

If we have given the _personal data_ to any third parties, we will tell those third parties that we have received a request to restrict the use of your _personal data_ , unless this proves impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. Those third parties should also rectify the _personal data_ they hold - however, we will not be in a position to audit those third parties to ensure that the rectification has occurred.

_Withdrawing your consent._ Where we are relying on consent to process your personal data (for example consent to receive marketing) you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

### Your rights - individuals outside the European Union

_Accessing Account Information._ We will provide you with the means to ensure that personally identifiable information in your web account file is correct and current. You may review this information by contacting us by sending an email to our support attendant – [privacy@topresume.com.](mailto:privacy@topresume.com)

_A Record of Data Transfer._ TopResume will provide the right to request and receive, once a year and free of charge, information about third parties to whom we have disclosed certain types of personal information (if any) about you for our direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, and a description of the categories of personal information shared. To make such a request, please send an email to [privacy@topresume.com.](mailto:privacy@topresume.com) and please include the phrase "Personal Information Privacy Request" in the subject line, the domain name of the website you are inquiring about, along with your name, address and email address. At our option, we may respond to such requests by providing instructions about how our users can exercise their options to prevent our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

_California Online Privacy Protection Act._ As required by the California Online Privacy Protection Act ("California Act") and the California Business and Professions Code, this Privacy Policy identifies the categories of Personally Identifiable Information (as that term is defined above and in the California Act) that we collect through our website about individual consumers who use or visit our website and the categories of third-party persons or entities with whom such personally identifiable information may be shared. See more about the [California Act.](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf)

### Where we store and transfer your data

The EU and the United States. We have customers all over the world but to provide you with services, we store, use and transmit information only in the United States and the European Economic Area **(EEA)**.

In relation to personal data of individuals in the European Union, we may share your personal data within the Company. This may involve transferring your data outside the **EEA**. We may also share your data with trusted third parties who assist us in providing, improving, protecting and promoting our Services and this may also involve transferring your data outside the **EEA.** Whenever we transfer your personal data outside the **EEA,** we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * Where we transfer your data outside the EEA within the Company, your data will be transferred to the United States. The Company complies with the US-EU Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from the EEA. This means that we have certified that we adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles which require us to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the EEA and the US. To learn more about the Privacy Shield and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).
  * Where we transfer your data to third parties, we will transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission (for further details, see [Adequacy decisions of the European Commission)](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en), or we will use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe (for further details, see [International data transfers using model contracts).](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)

In compliance with the US-EU and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, we are committed to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with questions or concerns about the use of their Personal Data should contact us at: [dpo@talentinc.com](mailto:dpo@talentinc.com)

If your question or concern cannot be satisfied through this process we are further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under US-EU Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield to an independent dispute resolution mechanism operated by Judicial Arbitration and Mediation Services (JAMS).

If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by us, EU and Swiss individuals may bring a complaint before the JAM EU and Swiss Privacy Shield program can be found at: www.jamsadr.org. Finally, as a last resort and in limited situations, EU and Swiss individuals may seek redress from the Privacy Shield Panel, a binding arbitration mechanism. We are committed to cooperate with EU and Swiss data protection authorities (DPAs) and comply with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland.

### Changes to our Company

If we are involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition, or sale of our assets, your information may be transferred as part of that deal. We will notify you (e.g. via e-mail to the e-mail address associated with your account) of any such deal and outline your choices in that event.

We may revise this privacy policy from time to time and will post the most current version on our website. If a revision meaningfully reduces your rights, we will notify you.

### Contact

Have questions or concerns about our Services or our privacy policy? Contact us at [privacy@topresume.com.](mailto:privacy@topresume.com)
